<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-assassination-franz-ferdinand/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1914-06-29/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Francis Ferdinand, Nephew of Emperor
Francis Joseph, Killed in Bosnian Capital
an Hour After Warding Off
Bomb Which Injures Score.
..LAYER A SERVIAN SOCIALIST
Volley from Revolver Hits Archduke and Ducheas of
Hohenburg as They Are Driving Together in .Automobile
in Town of Sarajevo?New Heir, Charles
Joseph, 27 Years Old. *%
i u i-?;.:. ?., T?-* Tri'
Sarajevo, Bosnia, June 28.?The Archduke Francis Ferdinand.
h tir to the dual monarchy of Austria-Hungary, and his mor
g; natic wife, the Duchess of Hohenberg, were shot to death to-day
in the main street of this, the Bosnian capital. Bullets from a
m agazine revolver in the hands of an eighteen-year-old youth rid
dl id the heir apparent and his wife, and thus completed the grim
ta jk a madman had unsuccessfully attempted only a few hours
be fore by hurling a bomb at the royal automobile.
Another terrible chapter has thus been written into the tragic
ar id romantic history of the House of Hapsburg. and to-night the
ag td Emperor lies prostrated by the news in his summer place at
Is?:hl.
The flying bullets struck Francis Ferdinand full in the face.
O? le tore its way into the Duchess's body. Another pierced the
, great artery in her throat. As the blood gushed from her neck she
fel I senseless across her husband's knees.
An instant later he. too, sank to the floor of the car i~. a heap.
Be rth were rushed with all speed to the palace. But no help was
of Bvail. They died a few moments after they arrived.
ASSASSINATION CAREFULLY PLANNED.
The assassination had been carefully planned. It was while
the? heir t? the Austrian throne and the woman he had loved so
well were on their way to the town hall that Nedeljo Gabrinovics,
a j ourneyman printer, slung a smoking bomb at the royal automo?
bil e. It was while they were returning from the hall, perhaps an
hour later, that Gavrio Prinzip, a high school student, stood at the
, co rner of the Rudolfstrasse and poured his fusillade into the help
lesis couple. Again, an unexp.odcd bomb was found a few yards
aw fay from the scene of death. It had been flung in a corner by
, an Dthsr madman after he had learned of the success of Prinzip's
attack.
ARCHDUKE WAS INDIGNANT.
After the bomb exploded the Archduke and the Duchess
pr oceeded to the City Hall. The automobiles were fleet and the
refws had not yet filtered through the crowd in waiting. Indeed,
th ere had hardly been time to telephone. So the burgomaster was
astonished when he met his royal guests at the door to have his
cu stomary address of greeting interrupted by the snapping words
of Francis Ferdinand:
"Herr burgomaster, we come to pay you a visit and bombs are
th rown at us. It is an insult!"
Then his princely dignity overcame his indignation, and he
pa used and said :
"Now you may speak." .
After the ceremonies the Archduke and his wife announced
th**at they would visit the wounded members of their suite in the
hcepitals on their way to the palace. They set out in their ?car,
th fcs time protected by a cordon of police. They drove rapidly
do wn the Franz Josefstrasse and were nearing the Rudolfstrasse
wl len Prinzip, a pale faced boy?indeed, a mere stripling, but with
all the zeal of a fanatic shining in his countenance?popped out, ?af
the front rank of the crowd like a seed from an orange. No one
seemed exactly to realize what he meant to do. It was as real and
ar.| unreal as a moving picture.
MAGAZINE REVOLVER USED.
Just as the automobile slowed up on the turn into the Fran*.
Ji .sefstrasse the boy raised his arm from his side. The sunlight
si ruck on the dull steel of the magazine revolver and soldiers
1? aped to grab, the youth, but before they reached him he had ac
c*omplished his deed. It was with extreme difficulty that he was
ni ?scued from the infuriated crowd.
The first attack was filled with all the dramatic intensity and
suddenness with which the successful and unsuccessful attempts
an the lives of European monarchs have been attended. Sarajevo
V 'as en fete to welcome Francis Ferdinand and his wife. It was
a triumphal procession. Flags fluttered in the soft wind and gar?
lands hung from the windows. A great throng of picturesquely
??lothed peasants pushed and shoved against the detachment of
[(soldiers that held them good naturedly in check at the railway sta
l-tion where the couple were expected.
HEIR APPARENT UNGUARDED.
?There was no especial military preparation, however, as the
heir to the throne had always been regarded as so popular that no
. particular precautions were necessary. In -fact, the general feeling
\ that he would without doubt in the near future succeed to the
throne through the death of his uncle had clothed him with a sort
of affection that seemed to protect him.
With his wife and staff he came from the train to the auto?
mobile, and as the crowd cheered the royal procession started for
j the City Hall along the flag decorated road. A short three hun-J</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1914-06-29/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>AUSTRIAN HEIR AND HIS
WIFE SHOT TO DEATH
AETER ESCAPING BOMB
Archduke Franz Ferdinand and Morganatic Spouse Assas
sinated by Youth in Streets of Sarajevo After
Infernal Machine Hurled by Anarchistic
Compositor Fails to Explode
Until After They Pass.
COURTS OF EUROPE PLUNGED INTO MOURNING j
AGED EMPEROR MAY NOT SURVIVE THE SHOCK
Ej-t Cable to The Ws -r Bcnld
Sarajevo, Bosnia, June 28. The Archduke Franz Ferdinand, heir
to the throne of Austro-Hungary, and his morganatic Avife, the Duchess
of Hohenberg, were assassinated while driving through the streets of
this city this morning. They were shot to death after escaping a bomb
that was thrown at their motorcar and warded off by the archduke's
own arm.
They were on their way to a reception at the town hall when
the bomb was thrown. It did not explode until after the archduke's
car Tiad passed and the occupants of the next car, Count Boos Waldeck
and Col. Morizzi, the archduke's aid de camp were injured slightly.
Among the spectators six persons were more or less seriously hurt.
.. , -..,.
Trie perpetrator was a news
paper compositor named Cabrino-
vitch from Trevinje.
Angered by Attack.
The archduke ordered his car halted,
but after he had found out what had
happened he continued on his way to the
town hall, where the councillors with the
mayor at their head awaited them. The
mayor was about to begin bis address of
welcome when the archduke Interrupted
him angrily saying:
"Herr Buergermelster. It Is perfectly
scandalous. We have come to Sarajevo
on a visit and a bomb has been thrown
at us."
The archduke paused for a moment and
then said:
"Now you can go on." ,
Thereupon the mayor delivered his ad
dress to the archduke who made a suit
able reply. The public which by this
time had heard of the bomb attempt,
burst into loud cries of "hurrah."
Miots Rlns list
After going around the town hall for
half an hour the archduke started for the
Garrison Hospital to visit Col. Mori-xl.
who had been taken there after the out
rage. As the archduke reached the cor
ner of Rudolf street two pistol shots were
fired in rapid succession by a young man
named Gavro Prlnxlp. The first shot
struck the Duchess low down on the right
side, while the second hit the archduke
in the neck near the throat and pierced
the Jugular vein.
The duchess became unconscious imaii
diately and fell across the knee of ner
husband. The archduke also lost coi.
sciousness in a few seconds. The motor
car In which they were seated drove
straight to the palace, where army sur
geons rendered first aid. but in vain.
Neither the archduke nor the duchess
gave any sign of life, and, the head of
the hospital could only cerUfy that both
were dead.
Frared Second Attack.
The authors of both attacks, who wera
arrested promptly, are born Austrian-.
Cabrinovltch worked for a few weeks In
the government printing works at BU
grave. He returned to Sarajevo as a
Servian Chauvinist and made no conceal
ment of his sympathy with the king uf
Servla. Both he and the actual murdeicr
expressed themselves to the police in
most cynical terms about their crimes.
It appears that after the first attempt
on their lives the duchess did not want
the archduke to enter the motercar
again, but the governor of Bosnia. M.
Potlorek. said: "It's all over now. We
haven't got more than one murderer In
Sarajevo."
At this the archduke decided to enter
the car again.
Before their departure from Vienna on
the Journey to Sarajevo the archduke
and duchess went to the chapel In the
palace and spent a long time In prayer.
Recently the archduke has declared
more than once his conviction that he
would not die a natural death.
The mayor of Sarajevo Issued a procla
mation to Inhabitants denouncing the
crime and declaring that the confession
of the murderers proves beyond all
doubt that the bomb came from Bel
grave f.
Darta from Behind House.
The youth Prlnxlp, who fired the fatal
shots. Is only nineteen. He fired at the
archduke's head and must have been well
Instructed, for he apparenUy was aware
of the well-guarred secret that the arch
duke always wore a coat of silk woven
obliquely, which no weapon or bullet
could pierce. This fabric Is used for au
tomobile tires and Is puncture proof.
Later, details show that the assassin
darted from his hiding place behind a
house and actually got on the motorcar
In which the archduke and his wife were
sitting and took close aim. first at tne
archduke and then at the duchess.
The fact that no one stopped the as
sassin and that be was allowed to per
petrate the dastardly act Indicate that
that the conspiracy had been carefully</text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>   lllllllllllllllllllllllllllllllllllllllll
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-eugenics</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84023416/1904-08-05/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>A new science has been Inaugurated.
It is called "eugenics" and relates to
tho improvement of the race, chiefly In
a pby alcal way. In a word. It concern,
the breeding of stronger children. Pro
fenaor Francis Oaltou, the famous Eng
lish blologlHt, aays of the new science:
"The aim of eugenics Is to represent
each class or sect by Its best speci
mens, causing them to contribute more
tbun their proportion to the next gen
eration; that done, to leave them to
work out their common civilization In
their own way,"
What can a learned society do to
further such a aclem? Professor Gal-'
toiisuggests the" following 'tfourse tf
procedure: First, dissemination of a
knowledge of the laws of heredity so
fur as they are surely known and pro
motion of their further study; second,
historical Inquiry Into the rates with
which the various classes of society
have contributed to the population at
various times; third, systematic col
lection of facts showing the circum
stances in which large and thriving
families have most frequently originat
ed; fourth, a study of the influences
affecting marriage; - fifth, persistence
in setting forth the national Importance
of this kind of study. Says the writer
in conclusion:
"There are three stages to be passed
through before eugenics can be widely
practiced. First, It must be made' fa
miliar as an academic question until
Its exact Importance has been under
stood and accepted ub a fact; second
ly, It must be recognized as a subject
the practical development of which Is
In near prospect and requires serious
consideration; thirdly, It must be In
troduced Into the nationul conscience,
like a new religion. ' It has indeed
strong claims to become an orthodox
religious tenet of the future, for -eugenics
co-operates with the workings of
nature by securing that humanity shall
be represented by the fittest races.
Whnt nature does blindly, slowly and
ruthlessly man may do providently,
quickly and kindly. As it lies within
his power, so It becomes his duty to
work in that direction, Just as it Is his
duty to be charitable to those In mis
fortune. The Improvement of our stock
seems one of the highest objects that
can be reasonably attempted. We are
Ignorant of the ultimate destinies 'or
humanity, but feel perfectly Bure that
It Is as noble a work to raise Its level
as it would be disgraceful to abase It
I see no Impossibility in eugenics be
coming a religious dogma among man
kind, but Its detalW muBt first be work
ed out sedulously In the study. Over
zeal leading to hasty action would do
harm by holding out expectations of I
near golden age which would certainly
be falsified and cause the science to be
discredited. The first and main point
Is to secure the general intellectual ac
ceptance of eugenics as a hopeful and
most Important study. Then let Its
principles work Into the" heart of the
nation, which will gradually give prac
tical effect to them in ways that -we
may not wholly foresee."
It surely is time that matters of this
sort be talked of in purity and frank
ness. The upbuilding of the race In
every' possible ' way ' should become " a
passion with us all. The chief question
of life is not "What can Fdo to get
rich?" or "What can I do to become
notorious?" or even "What can I do to
save myself?" but "What can I do to
make the world better?"</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic> mmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmmm
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-american-female-pilots</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
