<topics>
	<topic>
		<id>
	https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-assassination-franz-ferdinand/selected-articles</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1914-06-29/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
					Francis Ferdinand, Nephew of Emperor
					Francis Joseph, Killed in Bosnian Capital
					an Hour After Warding Off
					Bomb Which Injures Score.
					..LAYER A SERVIAN SOCIALIST
					Volley from Revolver Hits Archduke and Ducheas of
					Hohenburg as They Are Driving Together in .Automobile
					in Town of Sarajevo?New Heir, Charles
					Joseph, 27 Years Old. *%
					i u i-?;.:. ?., T?-* Tri'
					Sarajevo, Bosnia, June 28.?The Archduke Francis Ferdinand.
					h tir to the dual monarchy of Austria-Hungary, and his mor
					g; natic wife, the Duchess of Hohenberg, were shot to death to-day
					in the main street of this, the Bosnian capital. Bullets from a
					m agazine revolver in the hands of an eighteen-year-old youth rid
					dl id the heir apparent and his wife, and thus completed the grim
					ta jk a madman had unsuccessfully attempted only a few hours
					be fore by hurling a bomb at the royal automobile.
					Another terrible chapter has thus been written into the tragic
					ar id romantic history of the House of Hapsburg. and to-night the
					ag td Emperor lies prostrated by the news in his summer place at
					Is?:hl.
					The flying bullets struck Francis Ferdinand full in the face.
					O? le tore its way into the Duchess's body. Another pierced the
					, great artery in her throat. As the blood gushed from her neck she
					fel I senseless across her husband's knees.
					An instant later he. too, sank to the floor of the car i~. a heap.
					Be rth were rushed with all speed to the palace. But no help was
					of Bvail. They died a few moments after they arrived.
					ASSASSINATION CAREFULLY PLANNED.
					The assassination had been carefully planned. It was while
					the? heir t? the Austrian throne and the woman he had loved so
					well were on their way to the town hall that Nedeljo Gabrinovics,
					a j ourneyman printer, slung a smoking bomb at the royal automo?
					bil e. It was while they were returning from the hall, perhaps an
					hour later, that Gavrio Prinzip, a high school student, stood at the
					, co rner of the Rudolfstrasse and poured his fusillade into the help
					lesis couple. Again, an unexp.odcd bomb was found a few yards
					aw fay from the scene of death. It had been flung in a corner by
					, an Dthsr madman after he had learned of the success of Prinzip's
					attack.
					ARCHDUKE WAS INDIGNANT.
					After the bomb exploded the Archduke and the Duchess
					pr oceeded to the City Hall. The automobiles were fleet and the
					refws had not yet filtered through the crowd in waiting. Indeed,
					th ere had hardly been time to telephone. So the burgomaster was
					astonished when he met his royal guests at the door to have his
					cu stomary address of greeting interrupted by the snapping words
					of Francis Ferdinand:
					"Herr burgomaster, we come to pay you a visit and bombs are
					th rown at us. It is an insult!"
					Then his princely dignity overcame his indignation, and he
					pa used and said :
					"Now you may speak." .
					After the ceremonies the Archduke and his wife announced
					th**at they would visit the wounded members of their suite in the
					hcepitals on their way to the palace. They set out in their ?car,
					th fcs time protected by a cordon of police. They drove rapidly
					do wn the Franz Josefstrasse and were nearing the Rudolfstrasse
					wl len Prinzip, a pale faced boy?indeed, a mere stripling, but with
					all the zeal of a fanatic shining in his countenance?popped out, ?af
					the front rank of the crowd like a seed from an orange. No one
					seemed exactly to realize what he meant to do. It was as real and
					ar.| unreal as a moving picture.
					MAGAZINE REVOLVER USED.
					Just as the automobile slowed up on the turn into the Fran*.
					Ji .sefstrasse the boy raised his arm from his side. The sunlight
					si ruck on the dull steel of the magazine revolver and soldiers
					1? aped to grab, the youth, but before they reached him he had ac
					c*omplished his deed. It was with extreme difficulty that he was
					ni ?scued from the infuriated crowd.
					The first attack was filled with all the dramatic intensity and
					suddenness with which the successful and unsuccessful attempts
					an the lives of European monarchs have been attended. Sarajevo
					V 'as en fete to welcome Francis Ferdinand and his wife. It was
					a triumphal procession. Flags fluttered in the soft wind and gar?
					lands hung from the windows. A great throng of picturesquely
					??lothed peasants pushed and shoved against the detachment of
					[(soldiers that held them good naturedly in check at the railway sta
					l-tion where the couple were expected.
					HEIR APPARENT UNGUARDED.
					?There was no especial military preparation, however, as the
					heir to the throne had always been regarded as so popular that no
					. particular precautions were necessary. In -fact, the general feeling
					\ that he would without doubt in the near future succeed to the
					throne through the death of his uncle had clothed him with a sort
					of affection that seemed to protect him.
					With his wife and staff he came from the train to the auto?
					mobile, and as the crowd cheered the royal procession started for
					j the City Hall along the flag decorated road. A short three hun-J</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1914-06-29/ed-1/seq-1</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
					AUSTRIAN HEIR AND HIS
					WIFE SHOT TO DEATH
					AETER ESCAPING BOMB
					Archduke Franz Ferdinand and Morganatic Spouse Assas
					sinated by Youth in Streets of Sarajevo After
					Infernal Machine Hurled by Anarchistic
					Compositor Fails to Explode
					Until After They Pass.
					COURTS OF EUROPE PLUNGED INTO MOURNING j
					AGED EMPEROR MAY NOT SURVIVE THE SHOCK
					Ej-t Cable to The Ws -r Bcnld
					Sarajevo, Bosnia, June 28. The Archduke Franz Ferdinand, heir
					to the throne of Austro-Hungary, and his morganatic Avife, the Duchess
					of Hohenberg, were assassinated while driving through the streets of
					this city this morning. They were shot to death after escaping a bomb
					that was thrown at their motorcar and warded off by the archduke's
					own arm.
					They were on their way to a reception at the town hall when
					the bomb was thrown. It did not explode until after the archduke's
					car Tiad passed and the occupants of the next car, Count Boos Waldeck
					and Col. Morizzi, the archduke's aid de camp were injured slightly.
					Among the spectators six persons were more or less seriously hurt.
					.. , -..,.
					Trie perpetrator was a news
					paper compositor named Cabrino-
					vitch from Trevinje.
					Angered by Attack.
					The archduke ordered his car halted,
					but after he had found out what had
					happened he continued on his way to the
					town hall, where the councillors with the
					mayor at their head awaited them. The
					mayor was about to begin bis address of
					welcome when the archduke Interrupted
					him angrily saying:
					"Herr Buergermelster. It Is perfectly
					scandalous. We have come to Sarajevo
					on a visit and a bomb has been thrown
					at us."
					The archduke paused for a moment and
					then said:
					"Now you can go on." ,
					Thereupon the mayor delivered his ad
					dress to the archduke who made a suit
					able reply. The public which by this
					time had heard of the bomb attempt,
					burst into loud cries of "hurrah."
					Miots Rlns list
					After going around the town hall for
					half an hour the archduke started for the
					Garrison Hospital to visit Col. Mori-xl.
					who had been taken there after the out
					rage. As the archduke reached the cor
					ner of Rudolf street two pistol shots were
					fired in rapid succession by a young man
					named Gavro Prlnxlp. The first shot
					struck the Duchess low down on the right
					side, while the second hit the archduke
					in the neck near the throat and pierced
					the Jugular vein.
					The duchess became unconscious imaii
					diately and fell across the knee of ner
					husband. The archduke also lost coi.
					sciousness in a few seconds. The motor
					car In which they were seated drove
					straight to the palace, where army sur
					geons rendered first aid. but in vain.
					Neither the archduke nor the duchess
					gave any sign of life, and, the head of
					the hospital could only cerUfy that both
					were dead.
					Frared Second Attack.
					The authors of both attacks, who wera
					arrested promptly, are born Austrian-.
					Cabrinovltch worked for a few weeks In
					the government printing works at BU
					grave. He returned to Sarajevo as a
					Servian Chauvinist and made no conceal
					ment of his sympathy with the king uf
					Servla. Both he and the actual murdeicr
					expressed themselves to the police in
					most cynical terms about their crimes.
					It appears that after the first attempt
					on their lives the duchess did not want
					the archduke to enter the motercar
					again, but the governor of Bosnia. M.
					Potlorek. said: "It's all over now. We
					haven't got more than one murderer In
					Sarajevo."
					At this the archduke decided to enter
					the car again.
					Before their departure from Vienna on
					the Journey to Sarajevo the archduke
					and duchess went to the chapel In the
					palace and spent a long time In prayer.
					Recently the archduke has declared
					more than once his conviction that he
					would not die a natural death.
					The mayor of Sarajevo Issued a procla
					mation to Inhabitants denouncing the
					crime and declaring that the confession
					of the murderers proves beyond all
					doubt that the bomb came from Bel
					grave f.
					Darta from Behind House.
					The youth Prlnxlp, who fired the fatal
					shots. Is only nineteen. He fired at the
					archduke's head and must have been well
					Instructed, for he apparenUy was aware
					of the well-guarred secret that the arch
					duke always wore a coat of silk woven
					obliquely, which no weapon or bullet
					could pierce. This fabric Is used for au
					tomobile tires and Is puncture proof.
					Later, details show that the assassin
					darted from his hiding place behind a
					house and actually got on the motorcar
					In which the archduke and his wife were
					sitting and took close aim. first at tne
					archduke and then at the duchess.
					The fact that no one stopped the as
					sassin and that be was allowed to per
					petrate the dastardly act Indicate that
					that the conspiracy had been carefully</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
	// {START 10 Assasination of ferd} <results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069168/1922-08-10/ed-1/seq-2</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text>
	<results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045499/1948-06-08/ed-1/seq-6</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text>
	<results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86075258/1948-02-11/ed-1/seq-12</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1955-09-25/ed-1/seq-19</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id></id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn92051342/1946-08-03/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1938-03-30/ed-1/seq-7</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1929-01-20/ed-1/seq-32</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2017236974/1941-02-06/ed-1/seq-12</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text><results>
	<result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84037526/1946-11-30/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	</text>
  <topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-early-eugenics</id>
    <results>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84023416/1904-08-05/ed-1/seq-1</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> A new science has been Inaugurated.
					It is called "eugenics" and relates to
					tho improvement of the race, chiefly In
					a pby alcal way. In a word. It concern,
					the breeding of stronger children. Pro
					fenaor Francis Oaltou, the famous Eng
					lish blologlHt, aays of the new science:
					"The aim of eugenics Is to represent
					each class or sect by Its best speci
					mens, causing them to contribute more
					tbun their proportion to the next gen
					eration; that done, to leave them to
					work out their common civilization In
					their own way,"
					What can a learned society do to
					further such a aclem? Professor Gal-'
					toiisuggests the" following 'tfourse tf
					procedure: First, dissemination of a
					knowledge of the laws of heredity so
					fur as they are surely known and pro
					motion of their further study; second,
					historical Inquiry Into the rates with
					which the various classes of society
					have contributed to the population at
					various times; third, systematic col
					lection of facts showing the circum
					stances in which large and thriving
					families have most frequently originat
					ed; fourth, a study of the influences
					affecting marriage; - fifth, persistence
					in setting forth the national Importance
					of this kind of study. Says the writer
					in conclusion:
					"There are three stages to be passed
					through before eugenics can be widely
					practiced. First, It must be made' fa
					miliar as an academic question until
					Its exact Importance has been under
					stood and accepted ub a fact; second
					ly, It must be recognized as a subject
					the practical development of which Is
					In near prospect and requires serious
					consideration; thirdly, It must be In
					troduced Into the nationul conscience,
					like a new religion. ' It has indeed
					strong claims to become an orthodox
					religious tenet of the future, for -eugenics
					co-operates with the workings of
					nature by securing that humanity shall
					be represented by the fittest races.
					Whnt nature does blindly, slowly and
					ruthlessly man may do providently,
					quickly and kindly. As it lies within
					his power, so It becomes his duty to
					work in that direction, Just as it Is his
					duty to be charitable to those In mis
					fortune. The Improvement of our stock
					seems one of the highest objects that
					can be reasonably attempted. We are
					Ignorant of the ultimate destinies 'or
					humanity, but feel perfectly Bure that
					It Is as noble a work to raise Its level
					as it would be disgraceful to abase It
					I see no Impossibility in eugenics be
					coming a religious dogma among man
					kind, but Its detalW muBt first be work
					ed out sedulously In the study. Over
					zeal leading to hasty action would do
					harm by holding out expectations of I
					near golden age which would certainly
					be falsified and cause the science to be
					discredited. The first and main point
					Is to secure the general intellectual ac
					ceptance of eugenics as a hopeful and
					most Important study. Then let Its
					principles work Into the" heart of the
					nation, which will gradually give prac
					tical effect to them in ways that -we
					may not wholly foresee."
					It surely is time that matters of this
					sort be talked of in purity and frank
					ness. The upbuilding of the race In
					every' possible ' way ' should become " a
					passion with us all. The chief question
					of life is not "What can Fdo to get
					rich?" or "What can I do to become
					notorious?" or even "What can I do to
					save myself?" but "What can I do to
					make the world better?"</text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1912-02-18/ed-1/seq-16</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text> Eugenists Would Improve Human Stock by Blotting Out Blood Taints CLASSED AS A
	HIGH GRADE IMBECILE, THIS GIRL. EIGHTEEN YEARS OLD. POSSESSES THE BRAIN OF A CHILD OF SEVEN.
	Scientists Are Studying How to Cut Down the Aw? ful Cost to Mankind of Bad Heredity, Which Often
	Swells from a Tiny Pool to a Black Ocean of Mental Defectiveness. IN A certain school In n South
	N? w J sey town is n young woman, rot i attractive in appearance, the story whose ancestry when
	it is published book form-and It is to be?is likely to ci ate a great deal of interest wherever
	it read. The contour and pigmentation of r features and the dark color A her ha which she ties
	with a pink ribbon, are si flclently Italian to warrant one in assui ing that she was ?of thai
	nationalitj if o *? n*. t her in Mulberry Bend Park. He) ; M genltors, however, lived In New
	J.-rsey le r before the American Revolution, and th<
descendants comprise a family well kn??v
In that state.
The girl herself, or perhaps one shou
call her a woman, for she is twenty-thr
years old, has the appearance of a well fe
ha ved person, and. Indeed, she is. i
medium height. BBS does not look her at
and if one w( Dg it she would
put down as In her early teens. Physical
she is a woman, however. Unfortunate!
mentally she Is not. Physically she
equipped with all the normal Instincts
womanhood: mentally, nature has left th?
ront rol in the hands of a child <>f ten yeai In other w??:?ls.
	she is not fitted to ta! care of herself in the average ? nvironme which the world offer*. Many
	porsoi would fln?l It difficult to believe this first glance, and not a few would be i elined to
	put her down as a woman of bl Instincts if ?he chanced to go wrong whi dependent upon her own
	resources HER PATHETIC RECORD. Her training in this school, which, it me be said, Is the \, w
	Jersey Training Bebo at Vlneiand, began twelve ar thirteen yeai ago. She was born in an
	almshous?-, tl fourth illegitimate child of a feebl.-min.lf mother, who was OM ai ? (godly of
	nlr and a servant. Hef father was n??nni physically and mentally. Although sin- hi been in
	school many years, she can rea only elementary books, being unable to d more than pick out words
	in a third reade ?be can write a chll Is letter, but does n' find pleasure either in jeadlnK Of
	wrltinj She Is, however, practically self-supportin In the s. hool. as she Is one of the bet
	workers among the pupils. While she car not plan her work, she can cut a dress, ru an electric
	sewing machine, take care c children ar.d s.-t a table. Curiously, how ever. In order to know
	how many plates t put upon the table It is necessary for he to know th.- persons wh?> are to use
	then ?lh* does not count the plates, but nam. them. The placing A a given number, i they be for
	st rann? is, is beyond her. This unfortunate srirl does not reaiiz wl at she owes to her
	Revolutionary ar restors, what their legacy to her wa-' Patient Investigation of over a year'
	duration, including the examination o records an?l talk?, with persons who pos sessed clews to
	the trail of the protoplasr which segmented into this girl and mor than 7*i0 other persons
	forming this re markahl? Illustration of n Jekyll an? Hyde inheritance, have led bark to a N'ev
	Jersey noldler of good family. He met I young woman of the woods near th? camp. He had, perhaps,
	never seen he before, and It Is believed he never again. The woman, who has been prove. to have
	been feeble-minded, went he way and he. the normal son of norma ? ancestry, went his. In due
	course a soi was born. A MOST LAMENTABLE CROP. The lad. when he grew up, was als<
subnormal In mental capacity. He mar
						ried a normal woman and had nlneteer
						children, the oldeat of whom had seven?
teen offspring. The taint was in th?
blood. From one of these the zealou*
but defective girl at Vlneiand is descend?
ed. To make a long story short, the
soldiers wild oats have borne frul!
through descending generations to the
extent of 381 persons, of whom 143 were
feeble-minded, 36 born illegitimately, 21
alcoholics, 3 epileptics, 3 criminals and
S keepers of houses of ill fame. Of the
number, 82 providentially died In Infancy
and 36 were socially unfit owing to dis?
ease and other causes. There were only
46 normal persons in the whole progeny.
ThiB Is only half the story, however.
The soldier afterward married a Rood,
normal Quaker woman of hla own "set"
and had live daughters and two sons.
Five of these heirs In turn had children
and their descendants have married Into
the very best families of New Jersey.
Of the 384 heirs of his blood in this
branch 36" aro known to have been nor?
mal and fifteen died In Infancy. Although
there is a love of alcoholic beverages In?
herent In the Dr. Jekyll branch. It has
been fought successfully by all except
two of the 884 persons comprising It.
One, through the introduction of a strain
of insanity by marriage, was insane and
one was socially unfit.
The story which lies behind the girl
at Vlneiand, who needs to he protected
through a considerable portion of her life
for her own ?good as well ns that of so
eiety, points several "morals." A certaii
well known publicist of this country ha
had a great deal to say about "race sul
dde" and the need for large famille*. [1
this family one feeble-minded hoy ha?
a.s many descendants a* seven norma
son;; and daughters on the other Sid?
The country would have been much I ?'t
ter ort without his progeny.
Investigation tends to prove that th?
feeble-minded have larger families thai
normal-minded persons, if the steriiiza
tlon law, which was recently adopted Ii
New Jersey, had been in the statute hook?
In the days of the Revolution and applle?
in the case of the woman of tl ?? woo? I
or her feeble-minded fon the saving t'
the state and to society would have beei
very great. Neither the woman nor bei
son would have suffered as a conaequenc?
And last, but n?>t least, the story Is an
important document in the case for tlM
Seteno? of eugenics.
It has been estimated that in the United
States one In every ihre" hundred person;
is f? ?1.1?-minded?that is, la?klng the men?
tal development to match the physical
.e'lUipnicnt. The rnlnils of these unfortu
nates stopped unf??l?iing when they wen
seven, eight, nine or ten yean old. Physi?
cally they have grown up with the Instincts
and capadtlea ?if normal persons, but they
without the control of an adult min?l.
According to the degn.f mental devel?
Opinent Which they oxliii.it. these defective?
are classified as morons, or feeble-minded
persons of high grade, imbecile:? and idiots
The first class is a particular menace to
society, because, in many ?as?s, owing to
the fairly good appearance of the subject,
It Is difficult to convince others that h?' or
she Is feeble-mlmt?ed an l ought to? segre
gated in s?>me way for the protection of th?
future ?if the community. Without full nor?
mal mental control of their Instincts, the
potyer to resist environment, the capacity
for choosing hetwe.'n th?' light an?! the
wrong, thiv form good toll for the devel?
opment of criminals, drunkards and prosti?
tutes. It is known lhat more than It P r
cent of criminals are feeble-minded. With?
out power to meet the complex ????ndlllons A
social environment they have falb-n be?
fore i;.
it has b. en demonstrated ?conclusively
that apllepsy is hereditary. Dated on data
???.11??ted at the State Village for Epileptics,
at Sklllman. N. J., It Is asserted that at
the present t?te of increase the number of
epileptic an?l feeble-minded in that state in
1940 will be double what it Is now, and that
the proportion will be one to every 125 ot
the population In 1970. If no mor?' re?
straint is Imposed upon epileptics than at
present, the population suffering from this
ailment will double in that state every
thirty years.
THE INSTANCES ARE MANY.
This problem of bad heredity finds Illus?
tration in many nlmshouses. A girl with?
out mental stamina to cope with her en?
vironment and Instincts finds herself about
to become a mother. Perhaps she Is a
servant In some household and is compelled
to leave her place. She goes to the alms
house and an Illegitimate child, probably
as feeble-minded as herself, Is bom. hhe
goes out In course of time, and perhaps In
a year or two returns for the same reason.
Among the inmates at Vlneland is a girl,
tho daughter of a feeble-minded woman and
a normal man, not united In matrimony.
The story of her ancestry was investigated
and It Is told by Dr. Goddard, the psychol?
ogist of the training school, In this lan?
guage :
"Here we have a feeble-minded woman
(referring to the inmate's mother) who has
had three husbands, including one 'who
was not her husband.' This woman was a
hamlsome girl, apparently having Inherited
some refinement from her mother, although
her father was a feeble-minded, alcoholic
brute. Somewhere about the age of seven?
teen or eighteen she went out to do house?
work In a family In one of the towns of
this state. She soon became the mother
of an illegitimate child. It was born In an
almshouse to which she fled after she had
been discharge?l from the home where she
had been at work.
"After this charitably disposed people
tried to do what they could for her, giving
ber a home for herself and her child in
return for the work which she could do.
However, she soon appeared in the same
condition. An effort was then mado to
discover the father of this second child, and
when he was found to be a drunk? n, feehle
mlnded epileptic living In tho neighborhood.
In order to save tho legitimacy of the child
her friends saw to It that a marriage cere?
mony took place. I?ater another feeble?
minded child was born to them.
"Then the whole family secured a home
with an unmarried farmer In the neigh?
borhood. They lived there together until an?
other child was forthcoming, which the
husband refused to own. When finally the
farmer acknowledged this child to be his
the same good friends Interfered, went into
the courts and procured a divorce from
the husband and had the woman married
to the father of the expected fourth child.
This proved jo be feeble-minded, and they
XLTHOUGti TfirfZTLElS YEf?f?S Old THIS
CflffL IS ONLY
SIVLN YZmS OLD MEIfTMCY
VHYSICBLLY H WO/?J?Jr,3ETW??]*r 2S ?iJO
TEAKS, MENTALLY SHE rs
ONLY S/X . SHE H?S f?f?E,alE.-tVNLEU SISTER
have had four other feeble-minded children,
making elrht in all, r-orn of this woman
"This woman had four feeble-minded
brothers and sisterr. These are all mar?
ried and have children The younger sit?
ter marri"d a feeble-minded man and had
f.irec children. Two of these are lasM*?
minded and the other died in Infancy.
There were six other brothers and sisters
who died In Infancy."
Portions of this story could be dupli?
cated In a large proportion of the towns
and cities of the Enited States. It has
characteristics which will be recognized as
familiar by th? kindly disposed of these
communities.
The biologist has demonstrated that cer?
tain defects are transmissible and their
presence Ifl the next generation can be
foretold. The .eugonlst. therefore, s'cklni?
"the Improvement of tho stock," must de?
vise some means of stopping the flow of
the taint. Segregation and ftTtllzatl' n
have been suggested
The biologist has also demonstrated that
good qualities can be passed on. The
eugeni-t Is following him up by pointing
out that the human race should not only
be relieved of the Incubus of the unfit, but
improved by the Introduction of qualities
which will fit It to cope with the increas?
ingly complex problems which are being
thrown upon it by Its p?rslstent efforts t?i
conquer the forces of nature. That there
In a growing feeling thHt something can be
accomplished In this dln^ctlon has been
shown by the Increasing numbers who hav<
attended
						conferen<*?s on the subject at the
Erooklyn Institute of Arts and Sciences
this winter and the number of new b?wiks
which are now being Issued.
"But how are you going to Improve the
human race?" some one asks. "Who is to
decide what qualities the human race
should possess? You can develop horses
that will run well, or draw heavy loads, and
cows that will be excellent for milk or
butter production, but who Is to pick out
the type of man to be developed?"
The eugenist replies that those possess?
ing the most desirable natural qualities
from the human point of view should he
mated with families of normal character
DR. HENRY H. GODDARD.
Which have demonstrated raraclty for
maintaining their numbers He takes a
pHKaoui of the conservationist's book an?!
argues regarding the human protoplasm. In
the words of Saleeby: "There is no wealth
but life; and If th?- Inherent ??unlity of Ufa
fails, neither battleships, nor libraries, nor
symphonies, nor free trade, nor tartrt
reform, nor anything else will save a na?
tion."
In Knpland It has been demonstrated that
for some reason 12 per cent of the Indi- (
vlrluals of one generation are producing.
THE STORY OF A REVOLUTIONARY
SOLDI?R'S DESCENDANTS.
The hand on the right lower corner indi?
cates the illegitimate Heir of his blood
now in the Vineland institution for
feeble-minded. The 384 descendants of
himself end his normsl Qusker wife
include only four known to be sub-nor
mal. His own sneestry, ss the chart
shows, wss perfectly normsl. N?Nor?
mal. F?Feeble-minded. A square
maana a man, a circle a woman.
one-half of the children of the succeeding
generation, the other half being the prog>nv
	of the remaining SX per cent. This proportion apparently holds good in the different levels of
	society. In OttMT words. a small **TOUp ?>f MCfe ?las.?* possesses un? usual fertility. Th?
	eugenlst ask*; "Il th? !" any relation between this superfertillty an?i the posses? sion of
	desirable ar undesirable character? istics'* It has been asserted that In Eng? land to-day there
	Is .1 dearth of youthful ability In various walks of life. The num? ber of murders and homicides
	to a million persons is reportad to have nearly trebled In the last fifteen yeara, in that
	country the "defective" alasses doubled In number in the period bet u un i?;t ami IMC and in
	1S*?1 more than one-third of the Idiots and luna tits were legally married and f 1 ??a to re I
	toduce their kind. In the l'nlteil States the latlo of insane in the total population was Hi In
	lOt'.HiO In ?HE, as compared with ix."? In tin- ?ame num? ber in iw). About IMM trate suppoasd
	ta be Uasegregated. Two-thirds of the pau? pers In Institutions are reported to have ? hlldren.
	an?! to be themselves deficient The rough total of defective ami dependen! lias been estimated
	to he .l.ilOO.O??, or about S per cent of the population of the United Ptat?s. It has been shown
	la recent years. In England In particular, that the middle en?! upper classes, which supply the
	thlnk ??a*-. baders ami organizers, are decreasing In numbers and that the net fertility of the
	undesirables Is greater than the net fer? tility of the normal types of the more ea I able
	classes. Investigation suggests that ability can he transmitted. The class lists of Oxford for
	ninety two renn showed thai M pet cent Of those who won first honors had had fathers who had won
	first or s?*?'ond hon? ors, that tt per cent of the second honor men were the sons of men who
	had take 1 first or second honors in their day. and that of the ordinary degree men only 14 per
	cent had fathers of this class. It has also 1.9 fourni that marriage between IW0 famille
	Inheriting ability will result In a _real>r proportion of chlMrcn of ability than where one side
	of the house Is mediocre. I There are not a few famous illustrations^ THIS MAN, THIRTY-SEVEN
	YEARS OLD, HAS ONLY THE MENTALITY OF A CHILD OF EIGHT AND ONE-HALF YEARS. Startling Examples Are
	Many?A Single Instance. Here Recorded, Reveals the Extension of a Crop of Wild Oats Into a
	Morass of Hundreds of Wretched Lives. of the transmission of particular ebtlltj such as th.-
	Bach family, which pn musicians for eight generations, nt thl family, twenty-nine, mor? or less
	generall known, assembled al ?>n?- gathering. Th family of Titwn (Vlcelll) Included nln pointera
	of merit In the Darwin famll: there were! Erasmus; his gramlsor, .'liarles, the fa moil:-
	expound? -r "f th -, of evolution: franela Oalton, v.-h? . . .1 the Idea of his cousin, Charle
	Darwin, forward to th.- point of con selection and set people to thinking o eugenics," >>r the
	"improvement of th human stock'; a mathematical astror.o mer ?-f high rank, a professor of plan
	. ? Cambridge Unlveralty and ai inventor of scientific instruments Of pre ? Ision. In this
	country the Al*ms family, t? Abbott family and tha r-?* cher family ar notable. Particularly
	remarkable In thl category la the family of Jonathan Ed wards. Of tha UBi descendants Mentirle
	in ir?", according t?. Wlnehip'a account o ??.. ..-. wcer college graduate?, i Of aur greatest
	coll-ges an?l I ?profeiwors In colleges, besides many wh? were principals of other important
	educa tlonal Institutions; B physicians, many o whom were eminent; mora than M clergy men,
	missionaries ar theotoglcal pi?? :. .?filers In the army and navy ,.-? promlnenl authors and
	writer*, b] 1 whom M ?hooka ol merit tren written an? publish.-?! an?l II Important perio.il? al
	edited; mora than 100 lawyer?, of one was nur most eminent professor o law,' :in?l S?; M liel.l
	public oftlc* of whom i was V'lce-Prestdenl of tin I'nlted Siates. 1 w. r- l'n!t??d States S??n
	at.?is; others were I ?'"*? vriuirs. m?mbers 0 1 Congress, framera of state constitutions mayors
	??f cities and ministers to foretgi courts, and 12 railroads, tunny banks. In BUrOnce companlea
	and large Industria enterprises have been indebted to theh i management. "Almost if noi evcrv
	department of SO i dal progn sa and ??f th?* public weal ha. felt t??.- impulse of tills healthy
	and lonK lived family. It Is not known that any ?n. of them was ever convft ted A crime." WHEN
	THE DRAG IS REMOVED. The Stlgenlal believes that the humar ??toik can be developed Into families
	of thl? character wh?-n the drag of the until ha* . leen removed ; when th?- blokXfUl has traced
	'more fuiiy th? effect ?>f comblnatlona ol physical an?! psychic characteriati?ca, and when
	BOdety has been educated to the point Of ralslnK the requirements for marriage, For the
	elimination of the Incubus A defec? Uva stock eegreg mon and stertllaatlon have been suggested.
	Connecticut, Indiana and New Jersey have sterltsatio*. lawa Por the matin?: ?if the fit it has
	been proposed that persona be compelled to submit to exam? ination before they marry, and
	marriages of those who an- found unfit prohibited. In one of the Pacific colonlea of .'.rent
	Britain I it is reporte?! that this suggestion is made ? more practicable by simply requiring
	the examination, leaving It to the conscience.-: of tha parties t<> decide whether they shall
	a.-t i upon the resulta or not. The eugenlal ais?. I believes thai many of the fit who are not
	now permitteil t?> marrv should be allowed to do Fo. such Include clergymen and. in i England,
	nuraea Dr. Ooddard, of Vlneiand, said to _ rap. |iesfntati\e of The Tribune n few daya ago
	Ire-gardlng eugenics ?n.i what im.? been learned regar ling the transmissible charac? teristics
	of the unfit : "The ideal of eugenics BMBSJ to m?' to he the building up ?if a higher race by
	the elimination of the defectives and the im? provement of the stock, in r?sped t?. th. latter,
	I think, us we ?orne to know the laWI of heredity their application will become general among
	the Intelligent, and tha im? provement of the rH.*?- win become self? regulating. Those who are
	eonacfoita Of I strain of undesirable charactetlstii-s which are transmissible will then refrain
	from marriage. I'p to the present time w- have insufficient accurate knowledge regarding the
	influence of heredity, among the r. sults Is that some are denying themselves marriage
	needlessly. Take the matter ?f insanity. There are some kin.Is that are transmissible ; some
	that are hot It Is not clear In tegand to all of th.*m. Bugenista are working on this new.
	REACHING THE SOLUTION. "That la just When the work of the e,.ja? ulst comes In. The whole
	question of hered? ity and environment needs to he thrashed out. We have a study going pas jllMf
	"I1nv showing th.? two streams of environment and heredity. There Is an enormous group of
	degenerates mingled with the defectives. I went to a S.I1....I a Weeh ?ir two ?,K? ;,??! found a
	number of Children of low grado I parante that ?tested almost normal. This i suggested that the
	parent.?,, wn,, W(i_(i | aoma ?ases Of particularly KOOfl r a m 111 *** w. ?rere d?g?n?r?tes
	poswau. ?im i,Ufj Kone t,^ Pieces under the stress ?. environment Outwardly yon cannot always
	tall the dif? ferent. Tha defective and the degenerate l????k much alike frequently. Then? |M
	still much to be learned regarding the boundary lino between heredity a.id environment The two
	work tugetlmr. As Dr. c. U Dav? enport says, however, if you plant wheat you will always get
	wheat, but tf you plant it In r"?r soil you will get poor wheat and if In good soil you will get
	goo?l wheat. "There has n??t been a great anvnint of work don?* on different diseases. It has
	leen confln?d chh^fly to epilepsy, some types of insanity and fcMe-miml. l**ess. Proba? bly
	there are a great many of our func? tional diseases, like tuberculosis, which aro rot
	transmissible, bul week Mnstltutlona may be passed on. 1 believe that immunity to given diseases
	mav also be transmitted. 'An acquaintance told me that then Wttt a rtaln aliments which never
	worried hint ?and t?i the cure of which he gave little ?are. knowing from his family history
	that h?- ha?l little t?> fear from them. Mut his familiarity with the causes of death In a
	number of cases In his family le.l him to take marked pre?mutton? irhanaver ailing from anything
	which might lead to a Cer? tain ?trouble. It Is not impossible that the theory that the Jews,
	accustomed t?? l?f n I id anitary conditions in crowded ghettoes for centuries, have become
	immune to tu? bercular diseases and withstand th?*. peril* of congestion in our cities better
	than thus-? of other races. Dr. I?avenp-"rt is working on the heredity of disease, but then Is a
	?great deal to b- done. SOURCE OF THE CRIMINAL. Th* ?liminai. 1 think, is the product of
	feeble-mindedness ami c;\\ Ironment If von have a feeble niir.ileil person the prob? abilities
	are trememlou.sly strong that he "??. ill I econ-e a criminal. It would take a pretty bad
	environment to make a crim? inal out of a normal person. The w?i?l 'ariminul' might hist as well
	have been omitted from the N'ew Jersey sterl!lzati?ui lew, for the end woul?! have been gained
	just as well ami there would be lei tagOniStlc feeling regarding it Walle ?r* hav?> not obtained
	all the data we want on this subject, vet we have made several little etuilcs which indi at?
	that at l?sai . ter ? ent of the criminals are fech|e-minl?*?l. The superintendent of tn? HntJn
	u- f"im.i tory eays he thinks that i? pet cent ??f his inmates are feeble-minded Recently we
	:esie?l ?ne hundred Juvenile Court chll? dien in the detention house at Newark. Of these,
	thirty-four were found to be hackward, with tie chances that SOSSS of tl em WOUld later prove to
	be feeble? minded, atid the remainder were nil feeble? minded. These children were taken Just a
	they came. No selection was male. They were case? sufficiently important I ?r detention for
	further disposition ?if the ?ourt. "Until recently we have never include*! ???nona the mental
	defectives the hip h L-:,ide group. We have children who, to the uninitlateil. would never be
	?J**Cf*lh*d i*i feeble-minded That group is nia?le UP of at least 25 per cent of all the feehle
	mlnded. A boy who has just left us >??;i would say was a grumbler. You would m rer think he was
	feeble-minde?), and bit grouchlne** waa <>ne of the effects. He i-- a marked menace to society.
	Relative I) to this moron group the imb?cil? H t .-o great n menace, for lie is more apt t?. be
	placad In some Institution. These tvpes are capable of giving birth t?> chhV dun it i?
	queotloned by some whether the low grade Idiot has the power to brin?* ? iiiiuren Into the
	vvor'd "The menace of tin feeble-mindH and the imbecile ?s illustrated ia the case *' ?n
	aimsh'iuse la Chester, I'.nn. when i rasde te?ts. Then wen eight wane* in this be* stitution.
	all of whom would be.-ome moth? ers within six weeks. They were all im l?e?ll?'S. They had cone
	there to be cared for until their children were born, and then they would go out. t? conn- b*C_
	'he following year in the same condition. When the s clal workers ?want t* stir up the ani? mals
	let th??m go nt the RllMhOUM propo Slt'OH</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	// {START 10 EUGENICS} <results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1911-12-29/ed-1/seq-8</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-07-17/ed-2/seq-25</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	TWO LITTLE BOYS ARE PRETENDERS TO
			AUSTRIA'S CURSED THRONE
			London, England, July 17. Half a
			world apart, two pretty children are
			playing innocently in their luxurious
			homes.
			They are the rival heir-pretenders,
			to the throne of the Caesars!
			Meanwhile war in Europe and dis
			ruption of empire threaten to break
			The Pretenders Above Rudolph Hayne, son of Marie Vitsera Hayne,
			and great-grandson of Emperor Francis. Joseph. Below, Prince Maximilian,
			eldest son of the murdered Archduke Francis Ferdinand
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1934-01-14/ed-1/seq-85</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	The spark which resulted in world-wide conflagration. Arrest of the assassin after
			murder of Austrian Archduke Francis Ferdinand and wife during state visit to Sarajevo.
	June 28. 1914.
			Tunic of the murdered archduke, who was
			killed at the second attack of one day. ’
			One of the first of the Howitzer-type seige guns used
			by the Germans in the bombardment of Belgian forts.
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1934-01-07/ed-1/seq-20</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
	The drama . . . the pathos . . . the truth about war as only the
			camera can tell it, will be Brought to Star Readers every week
			beginning next Sunday.
			Many years were spent in ferreting out these pictures from secret
			governmental archives, private collections and from magazine and
			newspaper offices. From the assassination of Archduke Ferdinand,
			which precipitated it, to the*signing of the Armistice, which ended
			it, the whole photo history is brought to you in these special roto
			gravure sections each Sunday. Here is war! Authentic, uncensored
			4
			pictures giving a reality to war that words could never attain.1
			The entire series of eight-page rotogravure sections will be worthy
			of compilation for your own personal library.
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1941-04-27/ed-1/seq-104</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Early, too, in the Nazi conquest fell Sara
			jevo, adding to the dark history of the city
			where in June, 1914, the assassination of
			Archduke Ferdinand and his wife set the
			flames of the World War.
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1914-07-17/ed-1/seq-1</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
		</text><results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045211/1916-01-19/ed-1/seq-20/</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
		</text><results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86086499/1914-07-31/ed-1/seq-3</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>
	Two hundred persons were killed at Mostar In Herzegovina as a re
			sult of the assassination of Archduke Francis Ferdinand at Sarajevo. The
			Moslem Croatlana attacked the Serb quarters, bearing banners inscribed
			Death to the Murderous Serbs."
		</text>
	<results>
		<result>
		<id>hhttps://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1915-07-23/ed-2/seq-32</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
		</text><results>
		<result>
		<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85038485/1904-01-20/ed-1/seq-2</id>
	<rel>0</rel>
	<text>
		</text>
	</topic>
  <topic>
		<id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-american-female-pilots</id>
		<results>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045487/1912-01-19/ed-1/seq-32/</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
					LADY VIATORS' SPIRIT
					; - 'GOES "UP IN THE IR"
					. . New York, Jan. 19. War has
					broken out among the 'avatrices"
					of America, and war. among the
					female of the species is more
					deadly Oh, much more deadly,
					than ,war among the male !
					Charges of being a "grass cut
					ter" which in air language is
					equivalent to one colored gentle
					man telling another that a yellow
					streak runs up and down his back
					are being bandied across the
					1 continent. And rouge is not nec
					essary to redden the wrathy
					cheeks of the birdwomen.
					c Miss IBanche Scott, now in
					Los Angeles, began it. Miss
					Scott 'is not the possesor of an
					aviator's license, and perhaps she
					thinks she has been discriminat
					ed against in this matter. A . r
					Anyway ,"" Miss Scott, she up
					and said 'that Miss 'Harriet
					Quimby and Miss Mathilde Moi
					sant who. be it noted, possess
					aviator's' licenses were afraid to
					qompete with -her, because she
					was. too daring and spectacular"
					for them. ' ,
					r When this was reported to Miss
					Harriet Quimby, that lady drew
					a long , breath and assumed a
					s'cornfnl look.
					"Of course, she began, in icy
					tones, "you must understand that
					Miss Blanche Scott has never
					been awarde'd a license by the In
					ternational Aero club.
					"Under these circumstances, it
					is impossible for me, who has
					b'een -awarded a license, to chal-Jenge-
					her. . .
					"Otherwise"! should not hesi-
					tate to challenge Miss Scott
					"fie sides, this Miss Scott can
					nofdo the 'right hand turn.' That
					is 'one of the hardest things to do,
					and necessitates a1 spiral glide.
					I can do it.
					"The idea of Miss Scott saying
					that I am afraid to compete with
					her is too ridiculous to talk about
					I am not afraid of her, nor of any;
					man. Why, if I had the same pow
					er aeroplane 3S1 Claude Grabame
					White, I should not hesitate to
					challenge him for a race.
					"I don't believe hvthis circus
					flying. But 'I'm certainly not
					afraid of Miss Scott
					"Now if only she were.prqperly
					licensed, I should but .what is
					the use of talking she is NOTi
					licenced." </text>
			</result>
			<result>
				<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93055779/1911-07-26/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
				<rel>1</rel>
				<text>
					First Women To 'Drive Aeroplane Cross Country In New World
					Mivlineola, X. Y., July 25 Many aviators and other air enthusiasts are
	congratulating Miss Blanche
					Stuart Scott of Rochester, N. Y who drove an aeroplane across county in a twelve
	mile flight from
					the aviation field here in ten minutes. Miss Scott is the first woman to achieve
	such a feat in America.
					She ftew. one of Captain Thomas S. Baldwin's biplanes, overtaking a, mere man
	aviator who' had started
					first, circled over the village of W 'stbury and returned to the field, making a
	safe landing. Miss Scott
					once drove an automobile all the w.vv across the continent. She is a pupil of
	Captain Baldwin and has
					made several trial flights on the aviation field.
				</text>
			</result>
		</results>
	</topic>
</topics>
{10 women flight}
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85035678/1926-08-13/ed-1/seq-9</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	The Survival of the Fittest Since 1877
	ROTOGRAVURE SECTION
	FRIDAY. AUGUST 13, 1926
	ROTOGRAVURE SECTION
	(This Section Supplied by the National News Service, Philadelpha, Pa.)
	in dkatiure
	London—Photo shows three of the fleet of 16 seater
	Handley-Page planes, for the Imperial airways, cross
	channel service, which were named at Croyden, Eng
	land. just before this photo was taken.
	Tokio —At thp left In the group shown here are Mica
	Asana Malcla and Miss Shigeno Kide Japanese girl
	fliers and tlje first licensed women pilots in Japan.
	(International)
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88063294/1942-08-23/ed-1/seq-50</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	Expert American airwomen have
	joined the Air Transport Auxiliary of
	the RAP for the important job of
	ferrying planes from factory to war
	front. Photo shows Flight Capt.
	Jacqueline Cochran as she helps
	Louise Schurman to adjust her para*
	chuto before entering her plane.
	American
	WomenOver There
	By LOUIS REID
	SCORES of American
	women fliers are help
	ing Britain win the
	battle of the skies. They are
	members of the Air Transport
	Auxiliary, and they fly Spit
	fires and Hurricanes and Blen
	heim bombers from factories to
	RAP fields.
	One out of every nine women
	in the A. T. A. at present is an
	American, a fact which reflects
	great credit upon Flight Captain
	Jacqueline Cochran, America’s
	No. 1 woman flyer and holder of
	numerous speed and altitude
	records. It w’as Miss Cochran
	who, last Winter set about re
	cruiting volunteers from the
	3.258 licensed women pilots in
	the United States.
	WELL TRAINED
	Last June, It will be recalled,
	Miss Cochran piloted a Lock
	heed Hudson bomber across the
	Atlantic to England the first
	woman to perform such a Job.
	The flight made stronger her
	belief that America's women
	pilots should serve as wartime
	ferry flyers and thus free men
	for active combat duty. She
	began a recruiting tour of prin
	cipal cities, interviewed pilots
	who had at least 300 hours in
	the air. enlisted their support.
	At first their Job was to de
	liver trained Jplanes to pilot
	schools. Winning their wings
	at this work, they began to fly
	100 different types of British
	and American fighters and
	bombers to front-line stations.
	In hundreds of thousands of
	miles of flying over England
	there have been but two A. T. A.
	casualties. The death of Amy
	Johnson Mollison in a Channel
	crash Was one.
	According to Miss Cochran
	the women pilots in England
	have been doing a most helpful
	and outstanding Job In air
	transport.
	Illbll PAY
	“America'* women pilnls are
	giving great assistance.” she
	said. “At the same time they are
	being organlied and trained as
	a nucleus for a similar Amer
	ican air transport auxiliary when
	the need for such an organisa
	tion shall arise.”
	The American women are not
	serving in the Royal Air Force’s
	woman's auxiliary, which does
	ground duty exclusively. They
	wear the dark blue uniform of
	the A. T. A., a natty tunic and
	skirt, or trousers. On their
	shoulders appear the letters
	“U. S. A.”
	Their salaries, it is said,
	average 14.000 a year. This is
	somewhat more than British
	women fliers receive, since the
	Americana have a $25 a week
	expatriation allowance deposited
	to their credit in the United
	suites in addition to normal
	. British pay.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1957-06-09/ed-1/seq-166</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	What country has a squadron of jet aircraft
	flown entirely by 33 women pilots?
	Communist China. Women are also flying commercial
	airliners. There hasn't been an accident in five years.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1943-02-07/ed-1/seq-74</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	The Civil
	Air Patrol was the first flying agency to
	give women pilots a chance. Several all
	women squadrons have been established,
	and most of the WAF’s ferrying pilots
	have come from the Patrol.
	Often, entire communities help organize
	Patrol units. At Utica, Michigan, the land
	was donated for the field. Construction com
	panies loaned bulldozers to level the ground,
	and general equipment for building. Women
	flyers drove tractors, and men pilots turned
	carpenter to put up the headquarters build
	ing. Citizens volunteered both funds and flight
	equipment, and when the squadron left for
	wartime duty almost everyone in Utica felt a
	personal pride in the organization.
	After the outbreak of war, private flying
	was prohibited in an area along both coasts
	— except for the coastal-patrol units. But
	the grounded squadrons refused to quit. Some
	moved their bases inland, to carry on their
	wartime jobs. It has meant long, tedious trips
	week after week, from pilots’ homes to dis
	tant airports. Patrol members pool their cars,
	set up temporary camps at their own expense.
	C.A.P. pilots have made aerial surveys to
	see that no roof markings remain to guide
	enemy bombers. Others have spotted dozens
	of forest fires in time to check disastrous
	losses. The Patrol flies anti-sabotage guard
	around reservoirs, power plants, munitions
	factories, and other important points.
	Flying power and pipe lines, to spot breaks
	or leaks, and observing ice in the Great
	r air—, so that ore-boats can move at the earli
	est possible date — these are typical tasks
	the Civil Air Patrol has already taken over.
	Not long ago a war plant at Detroit was
	about to shut down when a vital machine
	broke. A Patrol flyer at Pittsburgh picked up
	the needed repair part, flew it to Detroit —
	and saved at least 1,000 man-hours for war
	production. Other C.A.P. pilots rush samples
	of ammunition from plants to proving
	grounds, to reduce the testing time so the
	plants can proceed with the run.
	Most C.A.P. squadrons are trained to re
	place aerial units of State Guards. This does
	not mean home duty. Orders to take over a
	distant and unfamiliar base may come with
	out warning. One Midwest squadron moved
	onto a strange field at dusk, erected tents,
	operations hut, radio shack, and made 175
	night landings before three in the morning.
	Ualimited luvict
	Along our coasts, and well inland. Patrol
	squadrons have become skilled in blocking
	airports against possible enemy use. Some
	C.A.P. units are training with parachutes,
	others with carrier pigeons, aerial pick-up of
	messages, camouflaging of planes and bases.
	In Russia, ^civilian flyers, armed with
	machine-guns, light bombs and hand gre
	nades, have strafed Nazi columns and helped
	annihilate enemy paratroopers. Others have
	ferried replacements, food and ammunition
	to guerrilla fighters behind the German
	lines.
	In each of these ways, and others more
	secret, the C:A.P. is ready to spring into
	action. But should such a test never come,
	the Patrol will have performed a tremendous
	war service.
	And when the war ends, the volunteer
	flyers will be ready for another important job
	— guiding and controlling the vast expansion
	in private flying which is sure to follow.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1942-10-06/ed-1/seq-28</id>
<rel>1
<rel>
<text>
	Women Pilots Wanted
	For Instructor Posts
	American women with private
	pilots' licenses are needed as instruc
	tors at salaries of $2,000 a year In
	junior ground schools, the Civil
	Service Commission announced yes
	terday.
	Immediate employment awaits 25
	women who possess these licenses,
	and a large number of additional
	appointments as instructors will be
	made in the near future, the com
	mission stated.
	"These highly important war jobs
	present a real opportunity for Amer
	ican women who can qualify to vol
	unteer their services in the Nation’s
	war program,” it said.
	No written tests are required for
	these instructor positions, and there
	are no age limits. Women pilots,
	however, who are doing war work of
	Exhibit to Aid French
	An exhibition of Napoleonic relics
	and old lace is being held, through
	October 13, at 1607 Connecticut ave
	nue N.W., for the benefit of the
	Fighting French Relief Committee,
	Inc. Countess de Castellane, chair
	man of the Washington branch of
	the Fighting French Relief Com
	mittee, Inc., is in charge of the col
	lection.
	equal skill should not apply, the
	commission said.
	The commission urged interested
	women pilots to submit their appli
	cations at once to the regional direc
	tor. 10th Civil Service Region, New
	Orleans, La. Application Form 57—
	covering these positions—is available
	at all first and second-class post
	offices, and at the commission's of
	fices in Washington.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015313/1929-11-01/ed-1/seq-6</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	105 WOMEN IN
	U. S. HAVE WON
	AIR LICENSES
	Nine Have Right to Pilot
	Transport Planes: In
	Commercial Work.
	PM Timm Sfirrint
	WASHINGTON. D. C, Nov. 1
	Modern women are taking to pilot
	ing aeroplanes faster than their
	mothers did to driving automobiles
	in the late nineties, and an
	aviatrix Is not a woman to be
	singled out for daring, according
	to the air travel division of the
	American Automobile Association.
	The A. A. A. air travel division
	bases its statement on the fact that
	there now are 103 women licensed
	pilots, although commercial aviation
	may be said to have really come to
	the forefront since the momentous
	flight of Colonel Lindbergh, early
	in 1926.
	It also Is borne out by the large
	number of women traveling by
	piane. who have not applied for a
	pilot's license, but have had a hand
	on the controls. There only were
	ninety automobiles in 1897 and the
	number jumped to 800 in 1899. but
	comparatively few were driven by
	women.
	Nine Transport Pilots
	“Os the total number of women
	licensed to pilot planes,” says the
	statement, ‘‘nine have transport
	licenses which gives them the right
	to pilot transport planes on com
	mercial airways, while eleven are in
	the limited class which confines;
	them to carrying passengers within
	ten miles of their home airport.
	"However, they are qualified to
	transport freight or express by |
	plane. Aside from these twenty;
	especially qualified women pilots,
	the remaining eighty-five can carry
	passengers as their guests, but not !
	in commercial travel. In this con
	nection, a striking feature is the
	fact that the list of women pilots ;
	shows by far the largest percentage
	in the west.”
	The A. A. A. air travel division
	pointed out that the iact that
	women are to the forefront in the
	turn of the nation toward air travel,
	has also increased the need for
	adequate information and service, i
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1945-11-11/ed-1/seq-95</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	Women in War
	Women service pilots were not an innovation in this last war.
	Back in 1917 women were trained for coast patrol duty.
	Women began taking over a number of men's jobs during
	World War I. In Washington they were employed os letter
	carriers.
	A policewoman was not an unusual sight tn the Capital dur
	ing First World War days. Here one directs traffic at Seventh
	ondSC streets N.W.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1955-05-22/ed-1/seq-90</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	Women Aviators to Fly
	In International Race
	Five flying Washington
	women will take to the air for
	the first international over
	water race for women pilots on
	June 9.
	Members of the Ninety-
	Nines, Inc., 26-year-old inter
	national association for women
	flyers, will fly from Washing
	ton National Airport to Ha
	vana, Cuba.
	Members of the Washington
	Chapter of the Ninety-Nines
	who will participate are Mrs.
	F. Lee Moore, chairman of the
	chapter, with her mother Mrs.
	Charles Cooper as co-pilot;
	Mrs. Wendell H. Moore, with
	Miss Eleanor Dafis as her co
	pilot; Miss Ada Mitchell, or
	ganizer of the FBI Flying Club,
	who will fly with Mrs. Don
	Thompson; Miss Louise Cal
	houn, with Miss Betty Fisher as
	co-pilot; and Mrs. Virginia
	Webb, who will fly with Jean
	Ross Howard as co-pilot.
	Guests of Government
	Co-sponsors of the race are
	the Florida Chapter of the
	Ninety-Nines and the Cuban
	Tourist Commission. While in
	Cuba, the pilots will be guests
	of the Cuban government and
	a special reception.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1944-10-04/ed-1/seq-30</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	AAF Decision to Drop
	All WASPS by Dec. 20
	Ends Long Dispute
	One of the hottest controversies
	ever encountered by .the Army Air
	Forces will 'be terminated Decem
	ber 20 with the separation' of the
	entire command of 1,000 Women Air
	Force Service pilots from further
	military duty.
	In making the announcement late
	yesterday, Gen. Henry H. Arnold
	said the vounteer WASP pilots will
	be replaced by men in mid-Decem
	ber ••ynless there are unexpected
	and much higher combat losses in
	the air war over Germany.”
	The House took this view of the
	situation several months ago when
	it killed the Costello bill to militarize
	the civilian women pilots. Oppo
	nents of the bill insisted that
	women should not be given expen
	sive basic and advanced flying train
	ing for jobs which could be filled
	by men already trained.
	Gen. Arnold had backed the ex
	panding WASP program until the
	House took action. He then termi
	nated further recruiting, while an
	nouncing that women already in
	schools would complete their train
	ing.
	The decision announced by Gen.
	Arnold yesterday followed a recom
	mendation last August by Jacque
	line Cochran, director of the WASPS,
	that the group be taken into the
	Army Air Forces or disbanded.
	Release of the women pilots, the
	AAF said, ‘‘was based on present
	indications that by mid-December
	there will be sufficient male pilots
	available to fill all flying assign
	ments in the United States and
	overseas.”
	Only two days ago the AAF an
	nounced that its reservoir of trained
	pilots was sufficient to allow a time
	extension of its flight training
	courses.
</text>
<results>
<result>
<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1945-11-11/ed-1/seq-96</id>
<rel>1</rel>
<text>
	Women service pilots in this lost wor were o bit more stream
	lined and their duties more varied, consisting chiefly of towing
	targets for artillery training and ferrying planes from factories.
	With the coming of the Second World War women again
	were employed as mail carriers.
	Bus ond streetcar jobs in Washington opened up for women
	in the second war. star stafr aild A p photos
</text>